Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Fencing
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting fencing
1922-2005
RU 989
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(3 boxes)
The materials consist of correspondence, reports, scorecards, publications and a videotape documenting the1986 Yale versus Penn fencing match.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The item was transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of correspondence, reports, scorecards, publications and a videotape documenting the1986 Yale versus Penn fencing match.
College athletes; College sports; Fencing; Motion pictures (visual works); Videotapes; Yale University -- Fencing; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Fencing materials, 1986-1994; Accession 2006-A-066
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Penn vs. Yale, 1986; 1 (Box 1)
  - Media guide, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
- Records of the fencing team, 1922-2005; Accession 2006-A-106
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Men's Fencing
    - Fencing Reports, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1936-1938, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
    - Scheduling, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Junior Varsity, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Accounting, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Z, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sport Organizations [Intercollegiate Fencing Association], 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Women's Fencing
    - General, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Z, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
    - Post Season, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Men's and Women's Fencing
    - Development, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - General, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19 - 20)
    - Captain Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Team Information, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yale Fencing Association, 1985-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Scorecards [Manager's Report], 1926, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Manager's Reports, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Publications (M&W), 1938-2005 (Box 1, Folder 26)